kfh.co.uk 2019-07-02

# KFH Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy explains how personal information is collected, used and disclosed by Kinleigh Limited, Kinleigh Folkard & Hayward Limited and Kinleigh Financial Services Limited (collectively, "Kinleigh Folkard & Hayward", "KFH", "we", "our" or "us"). This policy applies to users of our services and visitors to our sites.

By using our services or visiting our sites, to the extent permitted by applicable law, you are consenting to us gathering and processing information about you in accordance with this Policy, although consent may not be required for all of the elements described in this Policy.

#### What this Policy covers

Your privacy is important to us, and so is being transparent about how we collect, use and share information about you. This Policy is intended to help you understand:

##### What personal data we collect

##### How we use your personal data

##### Legal bases for processing your personal data

##### Aggregrated information

##### Retention periods

##### Cookies and tracking technologies

##### Who we share your personal data with

##### How we protect your personal data

##### Your rights over your personal data

##### External links

##### How to contact us

This Policy covers the information we collect about you when you use our services, visit our sites, or otherwise interact with KFH. This Policy also explains your rights over your personal data including how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you.

#### What personal data we collect

By using our services or visiting our sites, we may collect the following personal information: name, email address, telephone number and postal address. Depending on the service you are engaging with, we will collect other information relevant to and necessary for us to provide that service. For certain services, bank details or credit card information may be required.

We do not collect personal data considered as sensitive personal data such as health related information except when required for employees of KFH.

In addition, we may receive certain categories of personal data and some device information (such as your name, email, browsing history on our sites and other details) from sources other than you, such as from third party sites, applications and services.

#### How we use your personal data

We may use your information for the following purposes: to provide you with services and fulfil your requests, to provide the functionality offered on our site, to pay for services, to respond to or follow up on enquiries, to tailor your experience on our site including displaying relevant properties, to provide information and services to our customers, to perform statistical analysis, to protect against fraudulent, unauthorised or illegal activity, to comply with our policies, procedures and legal obligations and as otherwise consented to by you and as required or permitted by applicable law.

If you do not provide us with certain information, we may not be able to fulfil your request or provide certain services.

Generally we do not perform automated decision taking or ‘profiling’ by solely automatic means; there is human intervention in our processing and decision making.

#### Legal bases for processing personal data

When you engage with KFH, there are a number of legal bases under which we may request, process and use your data, including:

  * Asking for your consent to receive email marketing and to refer you to use our Londonwide Conveyancing, Financial Services or Survey services. Your consent is not assumed and you can withdraw or change your consent at any time.
  * Where we have a legal duty, such as complying with anti-money laundering legislation
  * To enable us to fulfil a contract
  * Legitimate interest, for example where we discuss related services or provide you with the details of properties to help with your property search. When you register your property search with KFH, you will be sent properties listed with surrounding branches to ensure we can best service your request and find you the right property.

Where the provision of data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or necessary to enter into or fulfil a contract, we will make this clear in our terms and conditions and contracts. Should the requested data be refused, it may not be possible to proceed with the service required.

#### Aggregated information

We may aggregate personal information collected from you and other customers as well as device information and location information (with your consent, where required) to provide general statistics that cannot be linked to you or any other specific user and with which we attempt to provide you with a better experience to improve our services.

#### Retention periods

We will retain your information for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Policy and as otherwise needed to comply with applicable law and internal company policies. The length of time between transactions in the industry has been taken into account when determining how long data is retained for.

#### Cookies and tracking technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by KFH and our partners, affiliates, analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analysing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

Cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit some websites. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. We use cookies to help identify your computer so we can tailor your user experience.

You can disable any cookies already stored on your computer, but these may stop our website from functioning properly. Please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) if you would like more information, including how to see what cookies have been stored in your web browser and how to manage and delete them.

Should you wish to opt out of Google Analytic tracking across all websites please visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Calls made to phone numbers on our website and marketing materials may be recorded for training purposes.

This website occasionally uses third party tools such as HotJar to understand what users interact with using surveys, screen recording and by visually representing clicks, taps and scrolling behaviour. These tools are constructed in a way to protect you and your information, but if you do wish to opt out by visiting this website: <https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out>.

Log File Information: Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page on our Service. When you access the Service, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, and other such information. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

The table below details the cookies we use across our website:

Purpose | Cookie lifetime | Cookie name  
---|---|---  
Remembers a user session ID and holds details of last search criteria/paging/context | Until browser is closed | ASP.NET_SessionId  
Acceptance of cookies | 12 months | Kfh-cookie-accept  
Authentication cookie for MyKFH. Persists user’s logged in state once logged into MyKFH | 12 months | MyKfh  
Stores the My KFH username for personalisation | 12 months | MyKfhName  
Optimizely cookies run A/B testing in order to develop and improve the website for future visitors. This cookie stores a visitor's unique Optimizely identifier using a combination of a timestamp and random number. No other information about you or your visits is stored. | 6 months | optimizelyEndUserId  
Optimizely cookie. As above, this cookie helps track data across redirects. | 6 months | optimizelyRedirectData  
Google Analytics cookies anonymously collect information about how visitors use our site.  
We use this information to develop and improve the website for future visitors. No personal information is collected or stored. | 24 months | _utma  
Google Analytics cookie as above | 30 minutes | _utmb  
Google Analytics cookie as above | Until browser is closed | _utmc  
Google Analytics cookie as above | 6 months | _utmz  
Google Analytics cookie as above | 30 minutes | _utmv  
  
We may share your data with third parties, to help manage our business and deliver services. These third parties may include but are not limited to:

  * Service providers, who help manage our IT and back office systems, and assist with our Customer Relationship Management activities, in particular Experian and Cheetah Digital
  * Credit and reference checking agencies including HomeLet
  * Suppliers who need to carry out work on your property
  * Our regulators, which may include the ICO, as well as other regulators and law enforcement agencies
  * Solicitors and other professional services firms (including our auditors)

#### How we protect your personal data

KFH values your privacy and data security. We use third party services to help maintain the security and performance of our systems and sites. Email monitoring software and network traffic firewalls are also used. You can be assured that any personal data we gather about you through our sites, email, social media, telephone or other means will not be passed on to any third party or organisation except in the instances outlined above.

We will never change our bank details during the course of a transaction. Always query emails supposedly from us where the sender’s email address does not match our domain kfh.co.uk, or where the format, style or content is not usual. We will always check when we receive an instruction to amend our record of a customer’s details.

If you receive something suspicious, please report it to our client liaison manager, email: [clientliaison@kfh.co.uk](mailto:clientliaison@kfh.co.uk),

#### Your rights over your personal data

Individuals have rights over their personal data, whether and how it is processed and other rights in law. If at any time you wish to make a subject access request or for your personal data to be amended or removed, please email [clientliaison@kfh.co.uk ](mailto:clientliaison@kfh.co.uk) or write to us at:

Client Liaison Manager

Kinleigh Folkard & Hayward

KFH House

5 Compton Road

London

SW19 7QA

You have the right to complain to the UK’s statutory authority for data protection, the Information Commissioner, whose contact details can be found at <https://ico.org.uk/>.

#### External Links

Please note this Policy does not apply to the practices of companies we do not own or control or to people that we do not employ or manage. We may link or otherwise provide access to third party sites. We provide these links for your convenience only. We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for third party sites, their content, or any goods or services available through these third party sites.

#### How to contact us

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about how we handle your personal data, you can contact our client liaison manager at [clientliaison@kfh.co.uk](mailto:clientliaison@kfh.co.uk)

If at any time we change our Privacy Policy, such changes will be made on this page and dated. This Policy was last updated on 24 May 2018.
